Amal Suthan

1114-1350 Danforth Road, Scarborough, ON M1J1G3 +16476084856

amalsuthan1994@gmail.com

SUMMARY

A passionate human who is a continuous learner in different streams of Information Technology. Currently work as a System Consultant with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. My passion for learning made me get knowledge and experience in a different field where Information Technology is essential. Experience in System Administrator and IT Technical Support using essential tools. Knowledge and experience in both Data Analytics and Cloud technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming/Scripting: Java, Python, Bash, PowerShell

Databases: MySQL, Postgres, Elasticsearch

Web Applications: Spring Boot, Agular, React

Operating System: Linux/Unix, Windows

Networking: TCP/IP, DNS, DHCP, SSH, SSL, HTTP, LAN, Wi-Fi, NAT, VPN

Cloud Platform: AWS, Azure

Security Tools: Nexus, SonarQube

CI/CD Tools: Jenkins, Gitlab, GitHub, Bitbucket, Maven

ITSM Tools: ServiceNow, SysAid

AWS Services: EC2, RDS, Elasticache, VPC, IAM, OpenSearch, RDS, S3, Lambda, CloudFront

Monitoring Tools: Datadog, Sentry, CloudWatch, CloudTrail

Container Tools: Kubernetes, Docker, AWS ECS

EDUCATION

AWS DevOps Course Sep 2022-current

Sazan Consulting Inc, Toronto, Ontario

Post-Graduate Certificate in Cloud Computing for Big Data 2020-2021

Lambton College, Toronto campus, Ontario

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science and Engineering

2013-2017 Mahatma Gandhi University, Kerala, India

EXPERIENCES

Systems Consultant Sep 2021-Current

Responsibilities:

Long View Systems

- Provide Tire 1 Support and Escalate the incidents to the correct Support team if cannot resolve the issue and manage the incident throughout its life cycle.
- Troubleshoot and diagnose technical issues remotely and resolve the tickets on time.
- Provide support to the end user with issues related to software and their computing platforms.
- Provide fully documented technical issues on the ticket management system, evaluate the client's urgency and impact of the incident and provide resolution of the incident.
- Track and escalate the outages.
- Identifying the improvement opportunities and reporting to peers and team lead to improved performance and output.

JR Systems Administrator Total Credit Recovery Limited

Responsibilities:

- Provide Tier 1 & 2 support and resolve problems to the end user's satisfaction concerning software, hardware, mobile devices, and network connectivity
- Monitor/respond quickly and effectively to requests received through the helpdesk ticketing system (SysAid), email, and phone
- Document and track issues, status and resolution using incident management tools
- Conduct ticket reviews, statistic reports and execute special projects as required
- Exercise sound judgment to escalate issues to senior members within the IT department
- Zoom Administration
- Fortinet VPN configuration and troubleshooting
- Create, delete and manage Email Address Exchange Admin Center
- Asset Management
- Manage user on DUO Admin
- Maintain user passwords, logins and access rights on a variety of systems including Microsoft Active Directory and Group Policy Controls
- Monitor and maintain applications and systems to maintain required compliance using ESET Security Management Center

IT Technical Support Lulu Group International

Dec 2017-Dec 2019

Responsibilities:

- Active Directory and Group Policy Management Controls
- Troubleshooting computer hardware, software and Mail Exchange Server issues
- Implement and test application servers, print servers and file servers
- Experience in CentOS/Ubuntu system administration
- Migrated objects between servers by using ADMT
- Inventory and Asset Management
- Maintain, configure and troubleshoot, solve network and printer issues
- Patching software and make the system up to date using SCCM
- Monitored Servers and Backups
- Ticket management using ServiceNow

Trainings & Certifications:

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate: Candidate ID: AWS01969717
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate (AZ-104): Microsoft Certification ID: 991890653
- Long View's Consulting 101
- Ticket management using ServiceNow
- Vulnerability management and Patch Management
- Agile and SDLC software development methodologies